Guide to the Patricia R. Cole and Nancy J. Flanakin National Center on Domestic and Sexual Violence Records
University of Houston Libraries
- DTFDV (Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence), id123184
  The DTFDV series contains printed materials, handwritten notes, note cards, correspondence, creative works, charts, publications, and ephemera 1996-2004 (101 folders). It is divided into 4 sub-series; Documents/Reports, Meetings, Site Visits, and Staff Documents. The series details the NCDSV's involvement with the Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence. Of note is the testimony of Deborah Tucker to the Senate of the United States providing an overview of the work done by the DTFDV. This document can be found under the sub-series, Staff Documents. The material has been arranged alphabetically by record type, and then within that, chronologically.
  - Documents/Reports, id123214
    - US Army Europe Stats, undated; id123519 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - US Army Assessment/Treatment Response, undated; id123520 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Military Protection Orders, undated; id123521 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Sample Memorandum of Agreement, undated; id123522 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Memorandum of Agreement between Hoke County, NC and Fort Bragg, undated; id123523 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Department of Defense Stats, undated; id123524 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - SOFA Host Nations, undated; id123525 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - DOD Response to DTFDV Second Year Report, undated; id123526 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Victim Safety Notes North Carolina Trip, undated; id123527 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Case Review Committee, 1996; id123528 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - San Diego Experiment, undated, 2000; id123529 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - DOD Report to Congress, 2000; id123530 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - DOD Public Affairs Plan, 2000; id123531 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - USAF Law Enforcement Response, 2000; id123532 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Data on Spouse Abuse in Military Brief, 2000; id123533 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Initial Report Media Response, 2001; id123534 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Misconduct by Civilians Information Paper, 2001; id123535 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Safety Planning, 2001; id123536 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Security Codes, 2001; id123537 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - DOD Response to DTFDV First Year Report, 2001; id123538 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - General Garry L. Parks Bio, 2002; id123539 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Victim Safety Protocol, 2002; id123540 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Law Enforcement Protocol, 2002; id123541 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Protocols for Third Year Report, 2002; id123542 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - NNEDV Response to DTFDV Second Report, 2002; id123543 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Fort Bragg EPICON Report, 2002; id123544 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - DOD and Lautenberg Amendment, 2002; id123545 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - HASC, 2003; id123546 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Meetings, id123215
    - April 2000 – Initial Meeting, id123548 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - July 2000, id123549 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - November 2000, id123550 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - January 2001, id123552 (Box 8, Folder 5-9)
    - March 2001, id123557 (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
    - June 2001, id123560 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - October 2001, id123561 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - November 2001, id123562 (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
    - January 2002, id123564 (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
    - March 2002, id123566 (Box 8, Folder 19-23)
    - November 2002, id123571 (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
    - DC Pentagon Meeting, 2003; id123573 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Site Visits/Conferences, id123216
    - Virginia Tech, 2000; id123576 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Fort Bragg and Camp Lejeune, 2000; id123577 (Box 8, Folder 28-30)
    - Victim Safety Workgroup, 2000; id123580 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Valinda Bolton’s European Site Visit folder (with European Calendar), 2001; id123581 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Valinda Bolton’s Europe travel papers, 2001; id123582 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tucker’s Europe travel papers, 2001; id123583 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - European Schedule, 2001; id123584 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Stuttgart, 2001; id123585 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Heidelberg, 2001; id123586 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Ansbach, 2001; id123587 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Hohenfels, 2001; id123588 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Kaiserslautern, 2001; id123589 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Dachau, 2001; id123590 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Rothenberg, 2001; id123591 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Nuremberg, 2001; id123592 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Ramstein, 2001; id123593 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Spangdahlem, 2001; id123594 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Naples, 2001; id123595 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - United States European Command (USEUCOM) Workgroup minutes, 2001; id123596 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Thank you letter, 2001; id123597 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Europe Trip notes and notecards Victim Safety Workgroup, 2001; id123598 (Box 9, Folder 19-21)
    - Pacific Command (PACOM) Calendar, 2001; id123616 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Pacific Trip – Tucker, 2001; id123617 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Yongsan & Area II, 2001; id123618 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Pacific Trip – Valinda, 2001; id123619 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - EUSA visit – South Korea, 2001; id123620 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Kaden, 2001; id123621 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Okinawa Women’s Group, 2001; id123622 (Box 9, Folder 28-29)
    - Japan, 2001; id123624 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Hawaiian Shelter, 2001; id123625 (Box 9, Folder 31-33)
    - Fort Bragg, 2002; id123628 (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
    - Executive Leadership Training, 2003; id123630 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Staff Documents, id123217
    - Handwritten notes, undated; id123632 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Tucker testimony to senate, undated; id123633 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Tucker travel forms, 2000; id123634 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2002; id123635 (Box 9, Folder 40-41)
    - Bolton/ Walsh Dallas Trip Itinerary, 2002; id123637 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Tucker memo to Senate, 2004; id123638 (Box 9, Folder 43)
- TCFV (Texas Council on Family Violence), id123185
  The TCFV series contains documents, financial reports, publications, a VHS tape, CDs, posters, ephemera, and correspondence (including Toby Myers letter of resignation from the Board) 1980-2007 (60 folders). The records have been divided into six sub-series Administration, Conferences, Ephemera, Manuals, National Domestic Violence Hotline, and Reports/Documents. Within the sub-series the material has been arranged alphabetically by record type.
  - Administration, id123218
    - Annual Reports, 1991-1996; id123640 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Board Of Directors Meeting Minutes & Agenda, 1997, 1998; id123641 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1993, 1995-1998, 2001, 2003; id123642 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Executive Director Monthly Update, 1993-1995; id123643 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Financial Reports, undated, 1995-1998; id123644 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Meetings & Agenda, 1995, 1998-2000; id123645 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Organizational Chart, 1994; id123646 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Policies and Procedures, undated, 1981, 1992, 1994, 1995,2003; id123647 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Work plans and strategies, undated, 1994-1998; id123648 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, id123219
    - Annual Conferences, 1984-2005; id123650 (Box 10, Folder 10-13)
    - Conferences/Workshops, 1983, 1990, 1995, 1998-2000, 2004; id123654 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Ephemera, id123220
    - Button and key chains, undated; id123657 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Legislative Agenda Summaries, 1993, 1995; id123658 (Box 10, Folder 17-18)
    - Men Make Choices kit, undated; id123660 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Newsletters, 1982-1983; id123661 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Service Directories, 1994, 1995, 1997, 2001, 2002; id123662 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Various Brochures/Pamphlets, undated, 1980, 1982, 1984-1985, 1990-1991, 1996-2000, 2002, 2004, 2007; id123663 (Box 10, Folder 22-30)
  - Manuals, id123221
    - Access to Safety, Justice and Opportunity, 2002; id123673 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Assisting Battered Immigrant Women, 2000; id123674 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Assisting Immigrant Survivors of Abuse, 2003; id123675 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Executive Director Resource Manual, 1995; id123676 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
    - A Guide to Traveling Safely, 2000; id123678 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Law Enforcement: A Model Response for Family Violence Cases, undated; id123679 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lesbian Battering Technical Assistance Packet, 1995; id123680 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Listen Up! A Guide to Training Communities on Domestic Violence, 1997; id123681 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Prosecution: A Model Response for Family Violence Cases, undated; id123682 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - TCFV Training Institute, undated; id123683 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Technical Assistance Manual for Volunteer Programs, 1995; id123684 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Technical Assistance Packet, 1998; id123685 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Texas Council On Family Violence (CD), 2003; id123686 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Working Together for Change, 1992; id123687 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - National Domestic Violence Hotline, id123222
    - Documents Regarding Statistics, 1996, 2002, 2003, 2005; id123689 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Ephemera, undated, 2000, 2001, 2004; id123690 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Hotlines Newsletter, 1995, 1999-2005; id123691 (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
    - Posters – oversized, undated; id123693 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Report on assessing service needs, 2005; id123694 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Reports/Documents, id123223
    - Battering Intervention and Prevention Project, 1994-1995, 1998; id123696 (Box 11, Folder 22-24)
    - Forms, undated, 1996, 1997; id123699 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Technical Assistance Log, undated, 1998; id123700 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Various Reports/Documents, undated, 1985, 1994-1998, 2003; id123701 (Box 11, Folder 27-30)
- Training/Education, id123186
  The Training/Education series contains documents, transparencies, published works, handwritten notes, and ephemera 1977-2007 (34 folders). It is divided into four sub-series; Educational Materials, Handouts, Manuals, and Slides/Presentations. This series reveals the consultation, training and education work of the NCDSV. The material has been arranged alphabetically by record type, and then within that, chronologically.
  - Educational Materials, id123224
    - Statewide Implementation of the Family Violence Option in Texas, 1999; id123706 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - DV Training Plan, 1999, 2000; id123707 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - Welfare Reform, 2000; id123709 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Domestic Violence Policy and Protocols, 2000; id123710 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Working with Local TANF, 2002; id123711 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Formal Papers (not written by NCDSV), undated, 1977, 1978, 1990, 1995, 1997; id123712 (Box 12, Folder 7-15)
  - Handouts, id123225
    - Personalized Safety Plans, undated; id123722 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Dating Violence, undated; id123723 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Rape and Sexual Assault, undated; id123724 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Organizational training, undated; id123725 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Various handouts on DV issues, undated, 1995, 1999; id123726 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Manuals, id123226
    - Domestic Violence and Child Support Enforcement Statewide Implementation of the Family, undated; id123728 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Establishing Expertise as an Ethical Expert Witness, 2007; id123729 (Box 12, Folder 22-23)
    - Getting There Safely, 2003; id123731 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - A Guided Discussion on the Prevention of Domestic and Sexual Violence, 2007; id123732 (Box 12, Folder 25-26)
    - A Guided Discussion on the Prevention of Domestic and Sexual Violence, 2007; id123733 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Technical Assistance Packet, 2002; id123734 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Slides/Presentations, id123227
    - Workplace response to DV, undated; id123736 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Kids at the crime scene, undated; id123737 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Counseling DV victims, undated; id123738 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Welfare and DV, 2000; id123739 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Women’s educational groups, 2002; id123740 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Coordinating community response, 2003; id123741 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Theater on DV, 2005; id123742 (Box 12, Folder 34)
- Tucker, Buel & Associates, id123187
  The small series of Tucker, Buel & Associates consists of printed documents, correspondence, transparencies, published materials, and ephemera 1995-1998 (12 folders). The series contains work of the Tucker, Buel & Associates organization. The material has been arranged alphabetically by record type.
  - Consultation on “Ring of Fire” Play, 1995; id123744 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1997-1998; id123745 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Conference on “The Silent Witness Initiative", 1997; id123746 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Conference on Women’s Health, 1998; id123747 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Domestic Violence Institute for Law Enforcement Trainers, 1997; id123748 (Box 12, Folder 39-41)
  - Membership in National Membership for Nonprofit Boards, 1997; id123751 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Resume, 1998; id123752 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Slides/Presentations, 1998; id123753 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Training Material, undated, 1998; id123754 (Box 12, Folder 45-46)